Guide to the Marcia Kirwan Standley papers SC1378
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Marcia Kirwan Standley papers
1951-1993
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Standley, Colleen
Standley, Marcia Kirwan
SC1378
9 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
Biographical / Historical
Marcia Kirwan Standley received an AB in Sociology from Stanford University in 1957, and an MSW from Boston University in 1965.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Colleen Standley, 2018.
Scope and Contents
Collection items include Standley's student work and notebooks from Stanford and Boston University; as well as items documenting her career in social work, both in Massachusetts and in California.
Women college students -- California -- Stanford.; Social service; Counseling.; Standley, Colleen; Standley, Marcia Kirwan
- Papers, Accession ARCH_2018_002
  - Student notebooks - Spanish (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Student notebook - French (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spanish notes (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exams (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Student papers (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Disorganization: Personal and Social, Soc/Anthro 126 (Course Reader), 1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Case study in obesity, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Engiish 2A, 1953 Summer (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - English 2B (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Psychology (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General biology, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hygiene (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - History 154, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Poliitical Science 1, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Western Civ, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Abnormal Psych 160, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Sociology 101, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Psychology 60; Sociology 110 113, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - History 100, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - History 170, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Classics H101, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Classics H102, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Sociology 128, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - History 11 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - History 141, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - History 101, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Sociology 1 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Sociology 144, 111, 155, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Notebook - The Red and the Black (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Notebook - "The Patriot" (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - MSW papers, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Fieldwork III IV (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Social Welfare 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Social Welfare III, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Community Organization I and II, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Community Organization Administration, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Thesis seminar (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Concord Family Service (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - A study of an out patient psychiatric clinic in a central hospital (thesis) Standly et al., 1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Boston University Student Curriculum Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Boston University Scool of Medicine Alumni Annual Report, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Fragment Society, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - U.C. Berkeley, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Concord Family Seminar (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Concord Family Service Society (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cambridge case work (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Notebook - Intake (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Boston housing information (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Massachusetts Memorial Hospitals (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Massachusetts Memorial Hospitals, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Massachusetts maps (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - County of Santa Clara (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Mental Research Institute, Palo Alto Medical Research Foundation, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Community Council of Northern Santa Clara County, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Santa Clara County Welfare Dept. Memos and notices (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - County of Santa Clara Social Services Agency (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - County of Santa Clara Social Services Agency (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Santa Clara County leave request (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Counseling/Family Therapy Newsletters, seminars, brochures (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Community Association for Retarded, Palo Alto (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - National Association of Social Workers (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous - Social work and welfare (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Child Abuse and the Mental Health Professional, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Principles of Psychology (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Telephone log, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Greeting cards (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Bookplates (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Buttons (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Anthropology 2, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sociology 126, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Classics 100, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Growth and Behavior, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Community Organization Administration, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Social processes, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Casework III, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - A Family attempts group therapy, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Boston University School of Social Work, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Notes, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Notes, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Typed work and papers (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Handwritten notes, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Case presentation (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Group work (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Social Processes (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Social Processes, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Course work (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Letter to Siegal (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Growth Behavior III exam, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Growth Behavior III (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Social Welfare, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Professional seminar, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Growth Behavior IV, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Family Group Therapy (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Casework III IV, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Social Service staff meetings (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Intake, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Community mental health planning (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Growth Behavior I and II (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Welfare cases (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Pamphlets (misc. topics - equality, fallout) (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Freedom School (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Survey Seminar on Family Therapy, Palo Alto, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Growth Behavior III, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - MSW papers, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Appreciation award, Nicholas P. Kirwan '26, Phi Gamma Delta, 1968 Oct 12 (Box 4)
  - Boston Freedom School elementary teachers' meetings (magnetic recording tape), 1964 Feb (Box 4)
  - photo album and cards (Box 4)
  - Services handbook: the world after SB 14 other stories (Box 4)
  - Album: Iran dating from March 26, 1951 (clippings) (Box 5)
  - Civil Defense supplement to the American Red Cross First Aid Textbook (Box 6)
  - Duck Club photographs (Box 6)
  - Indy '64? (three reels magnetic recording tape) (Box 6)
  - Indy '65 (two reels magnetic recording tape) (Box 6)
  - unlabeled (two reels magnetic recording tape) (Box 6)
  - Civil Defense metal helmet (Box 6)